XUJIE (JOE) ZHENG SOFTWARE

DEVELOPER, PENG

z374201743@gmail.com

■ 2374201743@gmail.c● 1445 South Park St, Halifax, NS B3J0B6

Senior software engineer with 5+ years' experience in architecting scalable web and native mobile solutions, managing development teams and delivering products from an idea to production. Comprehensive knowledge of javascript, swift and CI/CD. Strong background in creating maintainable high load architectures from scratch and refactoring existing systems to match new requirements.

Skills

TECH STACK

Angular

ReactJS

NodeJS

CSS

Python

C#

Swift Jenkins

Shell Script

MySQL

 ${\sf MogoDB}$

R

Embedded Processor

PROGRAMMING PRACTICES

Clean Architecture

SOLID Principle

Protocol Oriented

Programming

Object Oriented

Programming

Test Driven Development

Behaviour Driven Development

MVVM

MVC

Redux

LANGUAGE

Mandarin

Cantonese

Education

Queen's University
Master Management Analytics 2021

Dalhousie University

Bachelor Computer and Electrical Engineering 2015

Jan. 2020 to Dec. 2021

Sept. 2010 to Dec. 2015

Employment

IBM Canada

Mobile Lead Developer

iOS Platform Lead

Halifax, NS Oct. 2019 to Current

Led a full-stack agile team to continuously deliver native mobile apps for one of the largest Canadian companies in the airline industry, with more than 500 thousand daily active users. Collaborated with project managers and led the iOS, Android and NodeJS developers. Additionally, contributed to the DevOps automation process for deployment, code scan and source code management.

Halifax, NS Mar. 2019 to Oct. 2019

Designed the architecture of the iOS project by implementing best practices including and not limited to MVVM, protocol-oriented programming, and clean design with the SOLID principal. Led and mentored a team of iOS developers to follow Test Driven Development, and ensure best practice via code reviews. Dived deep into CoreData and implemented background auto-refresh from remote GraphQL services, also utilize CoreDate relationships and various MergePolicies to provide a smooth user experience.

Senior Angular Develope

Halifax, NS Feb. 2018 to Mar. 2019

Continuously deliver user-demanded features for the mobile app of one of the largest Canadian financial institutions. In return successfully increased the AppStore rating from 2.1 to 4.3. Implemented a Redux favour Angular 2+ hybrid mobile app, with NgRx and RxJS. Collaborated with system admins to simplify the process of showing situational maintenance messages using shell scripts.

WeUsThem

Senior Lead Software Engineer

Sept. 2016 to Dec. 2017

Delivered three award-winning hybrid mobile apps in the healthcare industry. Worked closely with healthcare researchers and the Telus Health development team, to define the features and scope of each project. Implemented Restful APIs middlewares with node.js, C# and python based on the project. Led the angular.js mobile team to implement a user-centric solution. Managed and deployed applications to both Apple AppStore and Google Play Store.

Software Engineer

Halifax, NS Nov. 2015 to Aug. 2016

Developed and maintained multiple websites with WordPress and PHP. Communicated with clients to understand their needs and respond to emerging situations. Developed websites for NSCAD (the most well known Canadian Art School), and campaign websites for Connect2Canada to gather Canadians in the US to celebrate Canada Day. In addition, responsible for maintaining the Customer Relationship Management framework for Connect2Canada.

Awards

IBM Global Business Services America · 2020 Innovation & Delivery Excellence Awards Leading one of the teams in the program to delivery.

Aug. 2011

Certification

Certified Professional in Agile Team Facilitation(ICP-ATF)ICAgile AWS Certified Cloud Practioner · Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Feb. 2019 to Current Feb. 2021 to Feb. 2024